Muhammad Waleed (Laravel Developer)

waleedinayatw97@gmail.com | +92-312-4975089 | www.linkedin.com/in/waleed-inayat-w97

https://waleed-inayat.vercel.app/ | Islamabad

OBJECTIVE

Hello! Waleed here, a web enthusiast passionate about turning creative ideas into user-friendly online experiences. As a digital craftsman, I find joy in taking on challenges and pushing myself to create something extraordinary. Passionate about Laravel.

I'm pushing my expertise to new heights while currently learning React JS to enhance my skill set, enhancing applications and providing users with an outstanding experience.

Let's connect and explore opportunities to build something amazing together!

EXPERIENCE

Laravel Developer at ADMK Solutions:

(AUG 2024 - PRESENT)

- As a Laravel developer at ADMK Solutions, I specialize in creating robust web applications and seamless API integrations to enhance user experiences.
- I work on optimizing backend performance, ensuring security, and delivering scalable solutions.
- Additionally, I collaborate closely with cross-functional teams to drive innovation and maintain high code quality standards.

Laravel Developer at UZAIR TECHNOLOGY:

(FEB 2023 - JUL 2024)

- At Uzair Technology, my main work is to create great and efficient web solutions.
- I focus very closely on details so the code will be at its finest quality.
- Dive across the Laravel framework to create web developments that exceed expectations.
- However, other times, I prefer to bring innovation and reliability, along with me into our projects.

PROJECTS:

- **VovoPlay.com**: A gaming platform inspired by GameDom, integrated with the PayTabs payment gateway for managing subscription plans using Auth and Capture transactions. Built with Laravel and React JS using Inertia JS.
- **GameDom.fun**: An online gaming platform offering diverse games, featuring MTN subscription integration via ComViva, coin distribution, friend networks, badge system, and more. Developed with Laravel and React JS using Inertia JS.
- **Shigoo Laundry App** A Multi-vendor's Laundry Service Platform. Build REST APIs for Mobile App and Admin Dashboard of Super Admin in Laravel. This system integrates effectively with order management, delivery tracking, and vendor coordination.
- **AI CoverGen** (Laravel + Livewire + TailwindCSS) AI Cover Voice Generating Website in which I integrated Stripe for secure payments, job scheduling for automated tasks, and AWS for file storage & uploads.

 ALL CARS - A Laravel website that shows the bidding history of cars for auction from the USA, Canada, and ZEA. The system processes thousands of LOTs and VINs daily to provide prices, build year, damage, mileage, and auction information. Designed safe payments by integrated stripe.

FYP PROJECT

TechTrack Advisor

- Created TechTrack Advisor with to help beginners who are often bewildered to choose a career in
 the tech industry. I used Gemini API for generating roadmaps and an AI model for personal
 suggestions about careers in Pakistan, this custom tech career GPS helps newcomers to navigate
 in the ever-evolving tech industry to succeed.
- Tech stack: Laravel, Livewire, Blade, Tailwind CSS

EDUCATION

BSCS @ KOHAT UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY

(2020 - 2024)

SKILLS

•	Laravel
•	Tailwind CSS

- Rest API
- CSS
- Click Up

- React JS
- Livewire
- Bootstrap
- PHP
- JavaScript

- Inertia JS
- Alpine JS
- SASS
- GitHub
- MySQL